Guide to the American Guild of Musical Artists Records WAG.209
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: General Files, 1918-1993
  - Performing Arts Committee (Committee to investigate methods to create interest in and support of performing arts), 1974-1975 (Box 12, Folder 49)
  - Petrill, Jack: Controversy re: Foreign Artists, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 50)
  - Philadelphia Choral Committee, 1943 (Box 12, Folder 51)
  - Philadelphia La Scala Opera Company, 1939, 1943 (Box 12, Folder 52)
  - Philadelphia office, 1938 (Box 12, Folder 53)
  - Philadelphia office, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 54)
  - Philadelphia office, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 55)
  - Philadelphia office, 1948-1949 (Box 12, Folder 56)
  - Presidential election (Kennedy vs. Nixon): Government support of arts, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Presidents of AGMA: Lists, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Puerto Rican artists: APATE, 1974-1975 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Questionnaires, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Reagan, Ronald, 1981-1982 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Red Cross, 1942-1944 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Redgrave, Vanessa and Redgrave Enterprises, Ltd. v. Boston Symphony Orchestra, 1983-1985 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Relief Fund, 1960-1993 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Relief Fund: Giovanni Millo trial, 1959, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Review Committee re: Auditor's report, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Rochester Grand Opera Company, 1943, 1947 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Rockefeller Music Fund, 1975-1979 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Rule re: Petitions (proposed), 1940 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Rules of the Stage (Canada), 1968 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - San Carlo Opera Company, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - San Francisco Ballet, 1943-1944 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - San Francisco Opera Association, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - San Francisco Opera Association, 1947-1949 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Sarnoff, Dorothy, Undated, 1943-1944 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Sassani, Jules, 1943-1944 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Schubel, Anton: Delegate, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Screen Actors Guild, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Segregated audiences: AGMA position on, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Sena, William, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Smallens, Alexander, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Society of Stage Directors and Choreographers, Inc., 1970, 1980-1982 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Spring Tour, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Staff, 1942-1943 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Staff, 1979-1981 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Staff memos, 1969-1983 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Standard Opera Committee, 1942-1943 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Study re: Admission of alien solo opera singers to the US, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Symphony orchestras: Negotiations with, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Theatre Authority, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Theatre Authority, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Theatrical employment agencies, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Tibbett, Lawrence, Undated, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Tibbett, Lawrence: Plaque presented by National Music Council, AGMA, Exxon, 1976-1981 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Tibbett, Lawrence: The Glory Road (privately printed), 1933 (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Ticket solicitations, 1950 (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Treasury Department ruling re: Withholding tax, 1943, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Twentieth Anniversary of AGMA: Conference Transcript, Jun 1957 (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - Twentieth Anniversary of AGMA: "The Coming of Age of the American Artist", 1957 (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - Union des Artistes de Montréal, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - U.S. copyright law, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 45)
  - W. Colston Leigh, Inc., 1943 (Box 13, Folder 46)
  - Wage Stabilization Act: AGMA treasury ruling, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 47)
  - Weinstat, Hertzel: Biographer of L. Tibbett, 1979-1983 (Box 13, Folder 48)
  - William Morris Agency, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 49)
  - Withholding tax, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 50)
  - Works Progress Administration, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 51)
  - Works Progress Administration: Teachers' Union, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 52)
  - World's Fair: Belgian Village, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 53)
  - Photographs, 1984, undated (Box 13, Folder 54)
- Series III: Guest Status Fees, ca. 1965-1991 (mostly 1970s).
  - Guest Status Fees (applications, filed alphabetically), ca.1965-1991 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Series IV: Oversize Scrapbooks and Ledger, 1936-1951
  - Clippings Scrapbook; Cash Receipts (Dues) Ledger, 1936, 1938-1940, 1950-1951 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook: Dues Cards (filed alphabetically), ca.1936-1940 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - AGMA award to Howard Laramy, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Series V: Archived Websites, September 2007-ongoing; 2 websites in two archived website.
  Scope and Content Note
  The American Guild of Musical Artists, AFL-CIO (AGMA), founded in 1936, is an American labor union that represents 8,000 current and retired opera singers, ballet and other dancers, opera directors, backstage production personnel at opera and dance companies, and figure skaters. AGMA is a branch of Associated Actors and Artistes of America. Earliest crawls of the website date from 2007, but the site is not naviagable until circa 2009. This iteration of the website contained news, contracts, audition information, board members, image galleries, and signatory institutions. In circa 2017-2018, the website went through a major redeisgn and included much content about the union, and included digitized copies of their publication AGMAzine, explainers for new members, polices on sexual harassement, visa consultation services, auditions listings, agreements and contracts, elections, news and event listings, and information on meetings and board members.
  AGMA Funds is a site that hosts informational resources about health and retirement benefits available to members of the American Guild of Musical Artists. It features FAQs and enrollment forms for a variety of benefit plans including health, dental, retirement, and pensions. The site also includes external links to Aetna resources and administrative information for plan administrators.
  The AGMA Relief Fund provides resources to American Guild of Musical Artists (AGMA) members in need, specifically surrounding the loss of work and money due to performance sector COVID-19 related closures. The website includes donation information, eligibility and application process, testimonials from recipients of the fund, and a newsletter.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  Accruals
  New site crawls are accrued semiannually.
  In 2020, https://www.musicalartists.org/ accruals were increased to biweekly. https://agmarelief.org/ is accrued monthly.
  Appraisal
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of musicalartists.org, agmarelief.org, and agmafunds.org in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.